Finding Aid for the Ruth Frey Axe Collection of Material about H.H. Bancroft and Company LSC.1427
UCLA Library Special Collections
Ruth Frey Axe collection of material about H.H. Bancroft and Company
1854-1977
UCLA Library Special Collections
Axe, Ruth Frey
LSC.1427
4.0 Linear Feet (8 boxes)
Collection consists of correspondence, manuscripts, publications, and ephemera by and about H.H. Bancroft and Co. and A.L. Bancroft and Co. Ruth Frey Axe compiled the collection to complete the Bancroft publications checklist started by Henry Wagner and Eleanor Bancroft.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Ruth Frey Axe, 1983.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942303433606533
Biography
Henry Raup Wagner was born Sept. 27,1862, in Philadelphia, PA; BA (1884) and LL.B. (1886), Yale Univ.; practiced law in Kansas City, MO, 1887-90; worked for Globe Smelting and Refining Co. (Denver) (1890-98), and Guggenheim Interests (later American Smelting and Refining Co.) (1898-1921); following his retirement in 1921, he devoted much of his time to writing on historical subjects; Wagner's interest in California printers and printing led him to collect Bancroft publications and prepare a bibliography on the subject; Eleanor Bancroft, then Asst to the Bancroft Library Director, assisted Wagner on this project; Wagner died Mar. 28, 1957; he bequeathed his collection of Bancroft imprints to the California Historical Society and left the nearly completed checklist project to Ruth Frey Axe. requesting that she see to its completion and publication.
Ruth Frey Axe was born in Chicago, IL and grew up in Los Angeles, CA; after two years at the Univ. of Vienna, she attended UCLA, and subsequently earned a master's degree at the Univ. of So. CA; she first met Henry Wagner at UCLA, and became his secretary and research assistant for nearly thirty years.
Hubert Howe Bancroft started publishing in 1857; his younger brother Albert Little Bancroft joined the business in 1859 making them close associates both in business and family life; in 1868 A.L. Bancroft and Co. came into existence and H.H. Bancroft and Co. was phased out; the brothers continued their association until 1886 when a fire and personal differences caused them to split; Albert went on to co-found the firm of Bancroft-Whitney.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of correspondence, manuscripts, publications, and ephemera by and about H.H. Bancroft and Co. and A.L. Bancroft and Co. Ruth Frey Axe compiled the collection to complete the Bancroft publications checklist started by Henry Wagner and Eleanor Bancroft.
Expanded Scope and Content Note
The collection comprises correspondence, manuscripts, publications, and ephemera by and about H.H. Bancroft & Co. and A.L. Bancroft & Co. These were compiled by Ruth Frey Axe for the completion of a Bancroft Publications Check-list begun by her late employer Henry Raup Wagner and Eleanor Ashby Bancroft, then Assistant to the Director of the Baacroft Library, The list below is to be used in conjunction with Mrs. Axe's own inventory of the collection, a copy of which is attached. The original typescript is in Box 1, f.1.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Box 1: Axe's inventory of items in collection; items #2-52.
Box 2: Items #53-68; #79-84 (folder 1 of 4). [For #69-78 see box 8]
Box 3: Items #84 (folder 2)-85 (folder 5 of 6).
Box 4: Items #85 (folder 6)-89; #91-103. [#90 not included]
Box 5: Items #104-118.
Box 6: #119-126; items not on checklist:
Bancroft Library tickets of admission
Bancroft Co. stationery
Evolution of a Library (1901)
Miscellaneous articles and ephemera re Hubert Howe Bancroft
Box 7: Item #127.
Box 8: Items #69-78.
Publishers and publishing -- California, Northern.; Bibliographies -- Archives.; A.L. Bancroft & Company; Axe, Ruth Frey--Archives.; Bancroft, Eleanor; H.H. Bancroft and Company; Wagner, Henry Raup, 1862-1957.
- Ephemera, 68 items
  Scope and Contents note
  Axe's inventory of items in collection; items #2-52
  - Catalogue of H.H. Bancroft & Co., 1857; ?cat. Z998B22c; 44 p. 18 cm. (Box 1)
    Booksellers, publishers and stationers, importers of law, schools medical, miscellaneous, blank books and stationery, Montgomery Streets San Francisco Contains an announcement of the establishment, dated "Montgomery Street, 1857.
    THE ONLY COPY KNOWN. The earliest Bancroft imprint.
    "In wonderful condition," says Glen Dawson. Should be preserved in case.
  - H.H. Bancroft & Co's Law Catalogue, Messrs. Little; Brown & Co's Miscellaneous Books, 1858; Item No. 2; 4 p. 21.5 cm. (Box 1)
    "Reinforced spine, otherwise fine. Needs better preservation. I have no record of any other copy."
  - This day published H.H. Bancroft & Co., San Francisco, November 11, 1861; Item No. 3; 4 pages, one side, 25x20 cm. (Box 1)
    Second page contains a list of books recently published and in course of publication, by H.H. Bancroft and Company. In perfect condition.
  - Office of The Pacific Encyclopedia, San Francisco, March 13, 1872; Item No. 4; 32 cm. One side only. (Box 1)
  - Bancroft's Diary for 1873, Item No. 5 (Box 1)
    Contains Useful Memoranda, and Tables for Reference published annually, San Francisco A.L. Bancroft & Company Booksellers & Stationers 721 Market Street MDCCCLXXIII.
    "One of a kind. Some most interesting entries. Seems to have been A.B.B's own notes. At end Acct. with Mrs. B."
  - Announcement of receipt of University Texts, 1873; Item No. 6; 1 page, 1 side only, 20x12.5 cm. (Box 1)
    Educational Department of A.L. Bancroft & Company Booksellers and Stationers to the Professors and Students of the University of California.
  - Emma Nevada in gold star, Item No. 7; Cards (ads.) (Box 1)
    - One side: The New Star Coal, Item No. 7 (Box 1)
    - Second side: all other Coals, Item No. 7 (Box 1)
    - Advertising Bancroft schoolbooks, Item No. 7; 9 cards, all different (Box 1)
    - One invitation to piano recital and reception., 1888; Item No. 7 (Box 1)
    - The Bancroft Company...other side ...take place at the History Building, Item No. 7 (Box 1)
      "Important as shows HHB also was in the music business as was ALB after they split in 1886."
    - "Gaudy" letterhead paper, Item No. 7 (Box 1)
  - Prospectus, The Book of the Season (The Native Races), 1875; Item No. 8; 13x20.5 cm. (Box 1)
    5 publishers listed, 5 vols completed
    A.L. Bancroft & Co.
    Prospectus
  - The Native Races Vol. I, N.Y., D. Appleton & Co., 1874; Item No. 9; 9 10.2x13.7 (Box 1)
  - Prospectus, 3 volumes completed, The Native Races, 1874; Item No. 10; 20.5 cm. 16 pages (Box 1)
    "Interesting letters of reviews."
  - What is being said of Mr. Hubert H. Bancroft and his literary work?, 1874; Item No. 11; 23 cm. 7 pages (Box 1)
  - Prospectus The Native Races, D. Appleton & Co., 1874; Item No. 12; 6 pages, 23.5 cm. (Box 1)
    Volume 1.
  - Prospectus The Native Races, [A.L. Bancroft & Co.], 1874; Item No. 13; 16 pages, 23 cm. (Box 1)
    This contains the important statement that H.H. Bancroft "determined to devoted his life to his literary labors in 1869 turned over the active management of his business to his brother Albert L. Bancroft, determined to devote the remainder of his to making available to the world the treasures he had accumulated."
  - The Adoption of the Pacific Coast Series of Readers, A.L. Bancroft & Co., San Francisco, January 22, 1875; Item No. 14; 32 pages, 21.5 cm. (Box 1)
  - To the Honorable County Board of Education, School Library Book, A.L. Bancroft & Co., 1875; Item No. 15; 1 page, 21 cm. (Box 1)
  - Memorial is of A.L. Bancroft & Co. to the Senate and Aseembly., 1876 January 3; Item No. 16; 6 pages, 21 cm. (Box 1)
  - Descriptive list of law publications of A.L. Bancroft & Co., San Francisco, 1877 March; Item No. 17; 16 pages, 23.5 cm. (Box 1)
  - Bancroft's Catalogue of American and English Medical Books, A.L. Bancroft & Co., [1875-1879]; Item No. 18; 46 pages, 23 cm. (Box 1)
    Prospectus.
  - Silver Carols songs, A.L. Bancroft & Co., 1879; Item No. 19; 4 pages, 16x23 cm. (Box 1)
  - Camp's New Physical Political Outline maps, 1879; Item No. 20; 1 page, both sides 15x16.5 cm. on gray paper (Box 1)
    General note
    "These maps have just been thoroughly revised to date, July 1, 1879."
  - [Exchange price list of A.L. Bancroft & Co. for schoolbooks], 1880 January; Item No. 21; 1 page. 22 cm. (Box 1)
  - White's Recitation Card, 1880; Item No. 22; 1 (broadside?) 42x23 cm. (Box 1)
  - Washington Territory Circular to school officers and teachers., 1880, after December 24; Item No. 23; 4 pages, 21.5 cm. (Box 1)
  - Gross Misrepresentation Oregon accusations, 1880; Item No. 24; 1 (broadside?) 28.5 cm. (Box 1)
  - The Notorious Syndicate Swindle. San Francisco Circular, 1880 May 18; Item No. 25; (broadside); 1 page. 26 cm. (Box 1)
  - To the Honorable State Board of Education of the State of Oregon, 1880 October 20; Item No. 26; 1 (broadside) 28 cm. (Box 1)
  - That Cheeky Circular II, 1880 October; Item No. 27; 4 pages, 28x22 cm. (Box 1)
  - [Further revision of the Bancroft readers], 1880; Item No. 28; 3 pages. 27 cm. 27.5 cm. (Box 1)
    Pages 2 and 3 Prices bid by San Francisco Board of Education for schoolbooks.
- Hard-cover Imprints, 11 imprints
  - Dwinelle, Rev. I.E. Relation of Religion to Civilization. San Francisco: A.L. Bancroft & Co. Printers, 1881., Item No. 29; PPW, 16 pages. 16x11 cm. (Box 1)
  - Bancroft's Christmas Messenger, 1881; Item No. 30; 9 prelim. 44 pages. 24 5x17 cm. (Box 1)
  - A Rare Chance to Make Money - Something that Every Household Should Have, Bancroft's Pictorial Chart, 1882; Item No. 31; 1 page, 1 side only, 21 5x14 cm. (Box 1)
  - Order of Publication of The Works of H.H. Bancroft, 1882?; Item No. 32; 1 page, 1 side only, 21x13 cm. (Box 1)
    "Important as early only to Vol. XXIII Alaska."
  - Bancroft's Works Order of Publication, 1883; Item No. 33; 1 page, 1 side only, 21x13 cm. (Box 1)
    Works to XXXIII.
  - Publisher's Notice of Deviation History of Pacific States, 1883 (?); Item No. 34; 1 page, 1 side only, 21x13 cm. on white paper (Box 1)
  - Publisher's Notice History of Pacific States [of Deviation], 1883?; Item No. 35; 1 page, 1 side only, 21x13 cm. on blue paper (Box 1)
  - 1883?, Item No. 36; 1 page, 1 side only, 21x13 cm. on blue paper (Box 1)
    re. History of Pacific States and Native Races.
  - The Story of Orpheus and Eurydice as presented at Baldwin Theater San Francisco, July 14, 1884; Item No. 37; (program story); PPW, 12 pages, ads. 19x13 cm. (Box 1)
  - Platt's Hall Thursday, May 8th, 1884, program, Item No. 38; 4 pages, 13x11 cm. (Box 1)
  - What Montana Educators say of Bancroft's Readers. San Francisco, A.L. Bancroft & Company, 1885; Item No. 39; PPW, 8 pages. 22.5x15 cm. (Box 1)
    Bancroft Library duplicate, acquired 1950.
  - Obras Históricas de Huber to H. Bancroft. Imprenta de A.L. Bancroft y Compañia, 1886?; Item No. 40; Yellow PPW, double-page map on green tinted paper, 32 pages. 21x14 cm (Box 1)
  - Prospectus of History of California, Vol.V, signed by A.L. Bancroft & Co., Publishers, 1886 August; Item No. 41; 1 page, proof sheet, 1 side only, 22x14 cm.; "many typos" (Box 1)
  - August Prospectus of History of California, Vol.V., signed by A.L. Bancroft & Co. Publishers, 1886; Item No. 42; 1 page, proof sheet, 1 side only, 22x14 cm.; "typos corrected" (Box 1)
    "The importance of these little proof sheets is the date of August 1886, which was after the great fire of The A.L. Bancroft & Co. Printing house and no copy of History of California Vol.V. with A.L. Bancroft & Co. imprint has been found to my knowledge. All bear the imprint of The History Co. which printed and published all H.H. Bancroft's work after the fire and split between the brothers."
  - History of Oregon, Vol. 1, Bancroft's Works, Vol. XXIX, San Francisco, The History Company, 1886 October 1; Item No. 43; 1 page. 1 side only, 21x14 cm. (Box 1)
  - Quarterly Book List of The Bancroft Company, Vol.1, No.1, 1887 July; Item No. 44; PPW, 14 pages, 24x15.5 cm. (Box 1)
    "Inside front cover is an Interesting account of The History Building, The History Company and The Bancroft Company.
    "On page 10, a picture of the Valencia Street Library, inside back cover a good picture of The History Building."
  - Quarterly Book List of the Bancroft Company, Vol.1, No.2, 1887 October; Item No. 45a; PPW, 15 pages. 24x15 cm. (Box 1)
  - Vol 1, No. 3, 1888 January; Item No. 45b; PPW (The Illustrated Christmas Number.) 32 pages. 24x15.5 cm. (Box 1)
    "It contains an 8 page (out of pagination) list of Harper & Bros. books for holiday buying, and an Interesting list, Pacific Coast Book Buyers registered at the Bancroft Company."
  - The Historical Works of Hubert Howe Bancroft with Special Reference to the Progress and Destiny of Texas, 1886-1887; Item No. 46; Red PPW, Double-page map, 21 page text, 23x15 cm. (Box 1)
  - The Historical Works of Hubert Howe Bancroft in their relation to the progress and destiny of the Pacific States, 1886-1887; Item No. 47; Red PPW, 24 pages, 23x15 cm. (Box 1)
    Page 14 refers to the fire of 1886.
- Typewritten material, 32 packages and envelopes
  - Obras Historicas de Huberto H. Bancroft su Relacion con el progreso y porvenir de America Central, 1889?; Item No. 48; Red PPW, 32 pages, double-page map front. 23 5x15 cm. (Box 1)
    Ban. Lib. dup. acquired 1950.
  - Historical Biography., 1889?; Item No. 49; Green PPW, 16 pages. 23 8x15 cm. (Box 1)
    re: Chronicles of the Kings.
    Bancroft Library duplicate acquired 1950.
  - Prospectus History of British Columbia, 1887 January; Item No. 50; 1 page. 1 side only, 22x14 cm. (Box 1)
  - Prospectus History of British Columbia, 1887; Item No. 51; 1 page. 1 side only, 22x14 cm. (Box 1)
  - Prospectus History of Central America, Vol. III, 1887 March; Item No. 52; 1 page. 1 side only, 19x12 cm. (Box 1)
  - Prospectus History of Central America, Vol. III, 1887 March; Item No. 53; 1 page. 1 side only, 22x14 cm. (Box 2)
  - Prospectus Popular Tribunals, Volume I, The History Company, 1887 July; Item No. 54; 1 page. 1 side only, 22x14 cm. (Box 2)
  - History of Utah, 1889; Item No. 55; Just published in one volume, 8vo, 808 pages....; No wrappers, staples, 22 pages. 22x15 cm. (Box 2)
    Reviews of book.
  - Catalogo de las obras Publicadas en Español por the History Company Libreros Editores, History Building, San Francisco, 1890; Item No. 56; Grey PPW 24 pages, 23x15 cm. (Box 2)
    Duplicate acquired 1950.
  - Postcard, San Francisco, November 20, 1890; Item No. 57 (Box 2)
    Bought of The History Company, Publishers 723 Market Street. One vol. 39 Bancroft's Works. Sheep 5 50. Memorandum invoice. Stamp in perfect condition. Photo of Kit Carson.
    1894
    Red PPW, 12 pages, 21x14 cm.
  - West American History Hubert Howe Bancroft Autograph Edition, New York, The Bancroft Company, 1902; Item No. 61; 1 page, proof sheet, 24x14.5 cm. (Box 2)
  - Receipt dated San Francisco, December 29, 1890. "On account of Bancroft's Works in full of all demands.", Item No. 62; 22x8.5 cm. signed by Drury (Box 2)
  - Receipt, The History Company, publishers of The Works of Hubert Howe Bancroft. San Francisco., 1890 December 6, 1890; Item No. 63; 22x14cm. (Box 2)
  - Prospectus for Literary Industries., Item No. 63; 16.5x10.5 cm. (Box 2)
  - Further Late and Earlier Notices of Mr. Bancroft and his books, undated; Item No. 63; grey, 4 pages, 14.5x8cm. (Box 2)
  - Holograph letter of Hubert Howe Bancroft to William Henry Knight from London, September 17, 1866; Item No. 64; Both sides of single page 20x13 cm. (Box 2)
    "Bancroft does not wish to begin publishing schoolbooks at this time."
  - Prospectus for Chronicle of The Kings, Item No. 65; Stiff PPW with deckle edges and decorated with pink block letters; C A crown and K. 18 p. 23.5x15.cm.; A huge folded chart at end tipped in: Chronicle of the Kings Plan or Framework or Structure 50x38 cm. (Box 2)
  - From Hubert H. Bancroft to Mr. Adolph Sutro, August 10, 1888; Item No. 66; Holograph letter [laid in] marked 'Personal' in red ink; 4 pages, 2 inscribed, 20x12 cm. (Box 2)
    Sutro Heights telling him he has been selected to be included in the Chronicle of the Kings.
  - California Publications, published by The Bancroft Company History Building. Market St. San Francisco, [1889]; Item No. 67; pink PPW, 4 pages. 15 x 8.5 cm. (Box 2)
    Very fine condition.
    Lists Harlan '88.
  - Analysis and Valuation of the Bancroft Library, 1886 June 11; Item No. 68; Grey plain wrapper tied with pink tape, printed on newsprint; 9 pages, 33x20 cm. (Box 2)
    (according to HRW probably by Bancroft himself)
- Bancroft hard-cover imprints
  - Prussia and the Franco-Prussian War, 1871; Item No. 69; 19.5x13 cm. 354 pages. 6 pages, ads. at end.; Poor condition. (Box 8)
    by John S.C. Abbott, Boston: Published by BB B. Russell. 55 Cornhill. Philadelphia: Quaker-City Publishing-House Chicago: James P. Snell. San Francisco: A.L. Bancroft & Co. Bort Hope, Ont. P.R. Randall & Co.
    "The only notice I have seen of this book was a squib in a Santa Barbara newspaper of 1871 saying 'An agent of A. L. Bancroft is in Santa Barbara selling Prussia, etc.'"
  - Caxton's Book: A collection of Essays, Poem, tales and sketches, by the late W. H. Rhodes. Edited by Daniel O'Connell. San Francisco: A. L. Bancroft and Company., 1876; Item No. 70; 300 pages, fair condition, 21.5x14.5 (Box 8)
  - The New Penelope and other stories and poems by Mrs. Frances Fuller Victor San Francisco: A. L. Bancroft & Company, printers, 1877; Item No. 71; 349 pages, 21.5x14.5 (Box 8)
  - The Poison Fountain or Anti-Parental Education., 1878; Item No. 72; 189 pages, 23.5x15 cm. (Box 8)
    Essays and discussions on the School question from a parental and non-sectarian standpoint by Zachary Montgomery, of the California Bar. San Francisco: Published by the author.
    This was printed by A.L. Bancroft & Co. although not stated here.
  - Pacific Coast Series The Pacific Coast Fourth Reader. Revised Edition. San Francisco: A.L. Bancroft & Company, publishers. Booksellers and Stationers., 1878; Item No. 73; 240 pages, 2 blue, 2 pages ads, 19x12.5 cm.; Excellent condition. (Box 8)
  - The Handy Companion for constant use. Hubbard Brothers. Publishers Philadelphia, Boston, New York, Cincinnati, Chicago, St. Louis, Kansas City, A. L. Bancroft & Co., San Francisco, 1883; Item No. 74; 256 pages, 14x9.5 cm.; Laid in: 1 page 191-192 Bazar receipts. (Box 8)
  - Our Lost Explorers: The narrative of the Jeannette Arctic Expedition, 1883; Item No. 75; 479 pages, 23x14.5 cm.; Bindings front and last pages loose. (Box 8)
    Maps, portraits, and numerous engravings; published by subscription only Hartford Conn: American Publishing Company San Prancisco: A. L. Bancroft & Co.
  - A Popular California Flora, or Manual of Botany for Beginners, by Volney Rattan. Sixth Revised Edition, San Francisco, A.L. Bancroft and Company., 1885; Item No. 76; 138 pages, 20x14.5 cm. (Box 8)
  - Salesman's Dummy History of Utah, Item No. 77; 24x16 cm. (Box 8)
    17 plates, 10 are black and white, 7 gaudy colors. 12 pages table of contents, 4 pages Authorities consulted. 51 sample pages of text, 2 sample pages of Index, 1 full page ad of History of Utah, 24 pages of order blanks, Sample of gaudy red and gold binding in back cover.
  - Shifting Scenes Poems by T.J. Richards San Francisco The Bancroft Company, 1889; Item No. 78; 164 pages, 18.5x13 cm.; excellent condition (Box 8)
  - Analysis and Valuation of the Bancroft Library, 1886; Item No. 79; Dated on back in pencil; 9 sheets, 35x19.5 cm.; Folded into grey cardboard tied with pink tape. (Box 2)
  - The Publications of the Bancroft Organizations with an Introduction by Henry R. Wagner Preface, Item No. 79; About 55 o.c. 55 pages. (Box 2, Folder 1A)
  - Original H.R. Wagner letter to Eleanor Bancroft., April 19, 1955; Item No. 80; 6 pages, HRW holograph laid in 153 pages. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous, including misrepresentations, Item No. 81 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - By John Howell of Misrepresentations in Bancroft work, Item No. 81; Xerox copy; Corrected misrepresentations on 6 pages, typewritten. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Reference to passages in the author's edition of the works of HHB which later editions were expurgated or revised John Howell, Item No. 81; Typed, 2 pages. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Publication Data on Bancroft's Works, Item No. 81; typewritten, 2 pages. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Bancroft's Works and their authors, Item No. 81; typewritten, 2 pages. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - HRW, Item No. 81; Holograph pages, 10 pages. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - The Library, Item No. 82 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Knight Gerson collection, undated; Item No. 82; clipping, no place; typewritten, library sale, 4 pages. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - The Evolotion of a Library, dictated by HRW, Item No. 82; 7 pages. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - The Bancroft Library, Item No. 82; 11 page. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Library sale, Item No. 82; (HRW holograph addition at end); 4 pages. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Traveler, Item No. 82; 2 pages. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Fisher's description of Bancroft, Item No. 82; 1 page (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Conclusion, Item No. 82; 6 pages. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Bancroft's Character, Item No. 82; 11 page. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - More conclusion, Item No. 82; 10 pages. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Chart of Book of the Fair (variations), Item No. 82; "pencil by me, 1 page" (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - White folder marked "Discard of HRW Bancroft", Item No. 83; mostly typewritten, ca. 100 pages. (Box 2)
  - Envelope addressed to Mr. J.L. Chernofsky, Item No. 84 (Box 3)
    Contains:
    Checklist of Publications H.H. Bancroft and Company
    1857 to 1870 Volume I by Henry R. Wagner and Eleanor Bancroft, completed and by Ruth Frey Axe
    157 typewritten pages ready for publication with one addition, from Mr. Michael Hackenburg of University of Chicago. Correspondence and xerox
    8 pages of Harry Clark's list of Bancroft Publications to year 1868
  - Checklist of Publications, A.L. Bancroft and Company, 1868 to 1886; Item No. 85; white folder; 250 typewritten pages, much interleaved with penciled pages of additions; 19 pages of Kary Clark's Checklist of A.L.B. and Co. in Bancroft Library; 20 typewritten pages of ALB checklist checked at Bancroft and UC libraries (Box 3, Box 4)
  - Bancroft Law
    - Idaho State Law Library, May 23, 1950; Item No. 86 (Box 4)
      re Idaho Reports Title page 1882.
    - Notes: Territories and States Laws, Statutes, Supreme Court, Item No. 86; 6 pages (Box 4)
    - Letters of L.A. County Law Bibliographer, Howard Jay Graham, January 1955; Item No. 86; 2 pages (Box 4)
      February 14, 1951
      February 2, 1951
      Answer HRW: February 6, 1951
      January 22, 1951; 4 p
      February 7, 1951
      Answer HRW February 9, 1951
      - Mr. Thomas S. Dabagh UCLA Law Library, January 10, 1951; Item No. 86 (Box 4)
    - California Supreme Court Reports, Item No. 86; 2 pages (Box 4)
    - Bibliography of California Reports, Item No. 86 (Box 4)
    - California Supreme Court Reports, Item No. 86; 1 page. (Box 4)
    - Letter of HRW to Mr.Graham, February 2, 1981; Item No. 86 (Box 4)
    - Letter of William B. Stern, January 9, 1951; Item No. 86 (Box 4)
    - Letter of HRW to Miss Caroline Wenzel California State Library, January 2, 1[?]; Item No. 86 (Box 4)
    - Letter of HRW to Johan Adams, January 15, 1951; Item No. 86 (Box 4)
      - Reply: January 17, 1951, Item No. 86 (Box 4)
    - Letter of HRW to Thomas Dabagh, UCLA Law Library, January 3, 1951; Item No. 86 (Box 4)
    - Notes Reports of Cases, Supreme Court, Item No. 86; newsprint, 1 yellow page. (Box 4)